<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <item name="about_town_text" format="string" type="string">
        One of the most scenic and historic spots in Southern California is nestled in the heart of Apple
        Country in Oak Glen, California where the summers are cooler and the winters dusted with
        snow. The five mile scenic loop of more than 30 ranches, farms and businesses are open year-
        round. You will see one of the most scenic byways Southern California has to offer. Enoch
        Parrish opened the first apple orchard in 1876, followed by the Wilshire family. The Rivers
        brothers and their families came to Oak Glen in 1906. Their orchard, Los Rios Rancho (Spanish
        for \"The Rivers Ranch\"), is still in operation, as are many of the other original orchards and
        ranches in the area. The Law family came into the area in the early 1930s and started their own
        apple orchard. They soon built the first roadside packinghouse, first restaurant and gift shops.
        Los Rios Rancho a 103-year-old ranch; Southern California\'s largest historical apple ranch,
        located in the heart of apple country, draws more than 300,000 visitors yearly who make the
        scenic drive to Oak Glen to pick apples, picnic and hike as well as enjoy the ranchos homemade
        apple pies and freshly pressed cider. Joseph E. Wilshire, who helped make the Oak Glen area
        famous for apple growing in the early 1900s, realized early on the suitability of The Glen for
        growing bountiful apples and began buying land where with his brothers George, Henry and
        Edward began the Wilshire legacy years earlier. The original settlers to Oak Glen were the
        Cahuilla and the Serrano Indians. They harvested acorns and ate blackberry and other local foods
        to survive. The unique climate and elevation was perfect for growing large black acorns, a
        favorite among the locals of their time. The evidence can still be found along the streambeds
        where the acorns were leached over 100 years ago. Although the main crop of Oak Glen has
        been apples since the 1940s, it hasn’t always been Oak Glen’s only crop. The potato along with
        many other crops, were grown in Oak Glen since the 1890s. After several farms began to sell
        apples individually to visitors, along with homemade apple pies, fresh apple cider and delicious
        apple butter from roadside stands, Oak Glen became an apple boom town overnight. The apple
        export trade has since virtually disappeared, and growers now earn much of their revenue from
        visitors who are allowed to pick the apples directly from the trees which not only offers guests a
        “back to nature” experience but also provides them with the freshest fruit with superior quality.
        Today many of the heirloom varieties of apples are still grown in the Glen, varieties you would
        be hard pressed to find anywhere else in the world, such as the Arkansas Black.
    </item>
    <item name="about_app_text" format="string" type="string">
        Welcome to beautiful Oak Glen, California and congratulations on your purchase of the “Oak Glen Discovery Book”.
        A fun and adventurous way to discover “The Glen”.\n
        \n
        The following pages of photographs were taken in various areas of Oak Glen. Your mission is to locate the items
        in the picture. The photos are arranged in sections or chapters. Each chapter title is a specific and well known
        destination in The Glen.\n
        \n
        To help with your “hunt” you will find, under each photo, the GPS coordinates of the subject shown. You can
        either input those coordinates manually into your smart device\'s map software or, better yet, download the CIM
        DISCOVERY APP from Google Play and simply scan the QR Code at the bottom of the page and follow the map to find
        the “Photo Treasure”.\n
        \n
        One of the cool things you get when you download the CIM DISCOVERY APP is access to something we call the CIM
        EDUCATIONAL BECONS. When you reach a specific photo location the app will automatically stream fun and
        educational (location specific) content to your smart device\'s. Its a great way to not only explore but also
        learn about the fascinating history and attractions of Oak Glen.\n
        \n
        \n
        To download the CIM DISCOVERY APP go to Google Play and search “CIM DISCOVERY”. This is a free app and, for
        those of us on a “Data Budget”, the content that is streamed to you does not require you to use your cellular
        data. Just turn on your smart devices WiFi and enjoy the show.\n
        \n
        “Happy Travels”,\n
        \n
        Cyrano
    </item>


</resources>