<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Discover Oak Glen</string>
    <string name="main_title">Oak Glen</string>
    <string name="subtitle">Discover</string>
    <string name="thumbnail_description">Chapter Preview</string>
    <string name="title_activity_chapter">ChapterActivity</string>
    <string name="page_image_description">Location Photo</string>
    <string name="previous_chapter">Previous Chapter</string>
    <string name="next_chapter">Next Chapter</string>
    <string name="shortlong_cutoff_ratio">"0.7"</string>
    <string name="eula_disagree">I Disagree</string>
    <string name="eula_agree">I Agree</string>
    <string name="about_town">About Oak Glen</string>
    <string name="about_app">About This App</string>
    <string name="title_activity_about_town">AboutTownActivity</string>
    <string name="about_short">About</string>
    <string name="wifi_auto_connect">Wi-Fi Auto-Connect</string>
    <string name="maps_by_scout">Map rendering powered by Scout</string>
    <string name="skobbler_attrib_url">http://developer.skobbler.com/attribution</string>
    <string name="feedback">Feedback</string>
    <string name="title_activity_feedback">Feedback</string>
    <string name="api_key_for_development_use_only" translatable="false">
        4cd6cf0a7b00b9bd5399e8b7f8229a92
    </string>
    <string name="feedback_intro">
        Thank you for using the Discover Glen Oak app.
        We\'d like to ask a few questions about your experience.
    </string>
    <string name="app_rating_question">How would you rate this app?</string>
    <string name="comments_question">Finally, what would you like to tell us about your experience with this app that has not been covered above?</string>
    <string name="recent_visit_question">Have you recently visited the town of Oak Glen?</string>
    <string name="visit_rating_question">How would you rate your visit?</string>
    <string name="relevance_question">How would you say this app enhanced your visit?</string>
    <string name="age_question">First, we\'d like to get an idea of who is using this app. What is your age?</string>
    <string name="permission_explanation">
        An important part of this discovery app\'s experience is the ability to connect to CIM EDUCATIONAL BEACONS. When you reach a
        specific photo location the app will automatically stream fun and educational content to your smart devices. This feature
        depends on specific secure wi-fi beacons, which have been strategically placed in specific locations. In order to
        automatically connect to these beacons, the Android system permissions to Access and Change Wi-Fi state, as well as to
        receive coarse location information, are required.\n\n
        To enable the CIM EDUCATIONAL BEACONS feature, please turn on Wi-Fi Auto-Connect from the app\'s menu, and accept the
        permissions if prompted. If you have permanently denied the permissions (by selecting the \"Never ask again\" checkbox), then
        you can re-enable them through your device\'s settings.
    </string>

    <string-array name="visitedOptions">
        <item>No, but I plan to soon</item>
        <item>No, and I don\'t plan to</item>
        <item>Yes, I have visited recently</item>
        <item>I\'m currently in Oak Glen</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="ageOptions">
        <item>Prefer not to answer</item>
        <item>Under 12</item>
        <item>12–17</item>
        <item>18–24</item>
        <item>25–34</item>
        <item>35–44</item>
        <item>45–54</item>
        <item>55–69</item>
        <item>70–89</item>
        <item>90 or higher</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="route_loading">Getting location and calculating route</string>
    <string name="map_loading">Map Loading</string>
    <string name="walking_distance">within walking distance</string>
    <string name="calculating_route">Calculating route</string>
    <string name="content_description_return">Return</string>

    <!--about app texts-->
    <string name="about_app_text_0" format="string" type="string">
        Welcome to beautiful Oak Glen, California and thank you for your purchase of the “Oak Glen
        Discovery eAdventure”. A fun and adventurous way to discover “The Glen”.\n
        \n
        <b>Start your Journey:</b>\n
        Your adventure begins when you either “tap”
    </string>

    <string name="about_app_text_1" format="string" type="string">
        on@ @
    </string>
    <string name="about_app_text_2" format="string" type="string">
        or@ @
    </string>

    <string name="about_app_text_3" format="string" type="string">
        \n
        By tapping on the@ @
    </string>

    <string name="about_app_text_4" format="string" type="string">
         a map will be displayed with your current location and “pins” that
        represent the locations of the hidden photo items. Tap on a pin and follow the map to the
        selected location.\n
        \n
    </string>

    <string name="about_app_text_5" format="string" type="string">
        If you should choose the@ @
    </string>

    <string name="about_app_text_6" format="string" type="string">
        a gallery of photographs will be displayed. Tap on a photo
        and the map will launch with guidance to the location of the selected item.\n
        \n
    </string>
    <string name="about_app_text_7" format="string" type="string">
        <b>Reach your Destination:</b>\n
        When you reach a destination look for the “Pop-up” text on your device for educational
        information and fun facts about the destination object.\n
        \n
        At some destinations, the app will automatically stream fun and educational (location specific)
        content to your smart device.\n
        \n
        <b>Keep Score:</b>\n
        Once you reach a destination a “Red Apple” will appear in the corner of the photo on your
        device. A “Red Apple” will also be added to the Main Page of this app. Locate all the Photo
        destinations and you may receive a valuable bonus!\n
        \n
        <b>One important note:</b> As you travel to your chosen location the map on your device will
        display the shortest, straight line, route. <b>PLEASE STAY ON DESIGNATED PATHS AND
        ROADWAYS!</b> Though the “straight line” path may be tempting it is important that you respect
        the area through which you are trekking.\n
        \n
        \n
        “Happy Travels”,\n
        \n
        Cyrano\n
    </string>


    <!--Pop-up messages-->
    <string name="aloha">There are dozens of beautiful waterfalls on Oahu. One of the most popular is located at the top end of
    the Manoa Valley and is where the beautiful Manoa Falls is located. It is also considered the 19th most
    haunted spot on Oahu. Long ago only the Ali\’i (royalty class) were allowed to dwell in this valley. They
    considered themselves living gods. On many nights (especially Po\’kane – night of the walking dead)
    their spirits walk the path there. It is also said that powerful entities that were never born also roam
    there.</string>

    <string name="ana_puka">Kaneana Cave is a magical site on Oahu\'s leeward (west) drift, practically as far away as you can get on
    the island close where the pavement ends. It sits at the base of a precipice outcropping and is around
    100 feet (30 m) high and 450 feet (137 m) deep. The cave is estimated to be around 150,000 years of
    age and was once submerged, cut out by the relentless ebb and flow of the sea.</string>


    <string name="hao_hakahaka">Kālua is a customary Hawaiian cooking strategy that uses an imu, a sort of underground broiler. The
    word kālua, which truly signifies "to cook in an underground broiler", may likewise be utilized to depict
    the sustenance cooked in this way, for example, kālua pig or kālua turkey, which are ordinarily served at
    luau feasts. Luau, in Hawaiian is really the name of the taro leaf, which when youthful and little is
    cooked like spinach. The customary luau was eaten on the floor over lauhala (leaves of the hala tree
    were weaved together) mats.</string>

    <string name="honu">When born, green sea turtles are only 5 cm (2 in) long. But they grow up to
    1.5 meters (5 ft) in length and can weigh over 300 kg (700 lbs), making them the largest of the hardshell
    sea turtles. Green sea turtles are able to hold their breath for hours at a time. Because they are coldblooded,
    the temperature of the water affects their ability to hold their breath. In colder water they can hold
    their breath for longer. To reach their nesting grounds, green turtles migrate long distances, traveling back
    to the beaches where they were born. After mating in the shallow waters near shore, female turtles climb
    onto the beach and lay their eggs in a pit. They lay 100-200 eggs at a time and leave them alone for 2
    months before they hatch. Once the baby turtles hatch, they must crawl to the water and avoid a multitude
    of predators, including birds and crabs.</string>

    <string name="hooikaika_kino">Warfare amongst the tribal chieftains (ali\'i) of the Hawaiian islands was common, with fierce battles
    typically fought to establish political boundaries and during succession disputes. Raiding was frequent.
    As the scale of warfare increased, the chieftains of Hawaii and Maui became increasingly powerful as
    they could draw on the larger populations and resources of their islands to support military operations.
    By the 1780s warfare was increasingly institutionalized, with formal rules and rituals. The ali\'i built and
    consecrated luakini (state temples) and conducted sacrifices, prayers, and ceremonies before launching
    campaigns. The mystical Kahunas were consulted to determine the best time for military operations. The
    chieftains increasingly drilled their troops and engaged in a technology race of sorts with firearms,
    cannon and other weapons acquired obtained from western traders. As wealth accumulated through
    trading with western visitors, opportunities for conflict between the chieftains also increased.</string>

    <string name="i_a">With a knowledge of fishing areas and seasons and an array of implements that included hooks and
    lines, lures, nets, basket traps, poisonous plants, and spears, a fisher supplied his family or his ali\‘i with
    fish and shellfish from streams, fishponds, reefs, and ocean. Sometimes the catch was so huge, fish
    could be fed to the pigs and dogs, with some left over to dry as food or fuel for fire; some was left to
    rot. Those fishers that could supply large amounts of fish from ponds or catches at sea were believed to
    possess mana kupua, or supernatural power, to attract fish at will or make them multiply. Successful
    fishing implements, such as hooks or cowry shell lures became famous and were prized, passed on to
    heirs, and sometimes fought over.</string>

    <string name="la_au">Ancient Hawaiians enjoyed sports and games throughout the year, men and women and all ages
    playing at any time except specific kapu days. The highlight of the sporting year was Makahiki, the
    four-month harvest festival that took place from mid-October to mid-February. Makahiki honored
    Lono, the god of rains and fertility, and sports competitions complemented the season\'s general
    mood of celebration and the kapu on warring activities and field and fishing labors.
    Most Hawaiian sports emphasized individual competition over team athletics. An important function
    of ancient games was to train warriors. Games that built strength, stamina, agility and facility with
    weapons such as spears and darts developed skills that were basic to the battlefield where hand-tohand
    combat prevailed. Hawaiian games in general emphasized skill over luck. Ali`i as well as
    maka`ainana (commoners) competed. The most skilled athletes competed against the champions of
    neighboring districts or the top athletes of other islands. Some games and their terminology varied
    from island to island, but tournament sports were played by common rules. Chiefs set aside large
    fields where they hosted competitions, the borders marked with colorful banners. Large tournaments
    could attract more than 8,000 spectators.
    Wagers and gambling were often important components of Hawaiian competition. Ali`i bet on the
    athletes they sponsored, risking great wealth or even personal freedom or life on the outcome.
    While many sports honed skills used in everyday life, hunting and fishing – with a very few
    exceptions – retained their purpose of providing food and were not pursued for sport. Rats were shot
    with bow and arrow and sharks were speared, hooked or snared. These two activities were the
    closest ancient Hawaiians came to hunting purely for sport.</string>

    <string name="lahalaha_wai">On the island of Oahu, in front of the Halekulani Hotel is an odd natural phenomenon that over the
    years has drawn visitors from around to world to experience its apparent powers. Known as the Healing
    Waters of Kawehewehe, it is a natural channel of water that runs through the reef below where large
    amounts of fresh spring water burbles up into the sea. Here, people who are sick, ill, or in pain come to
    seek relief for their symptoms and ailments.</string>

    <string name="lomi">Structures in customary Hawaiian culture were utilitarian with express assignments for each sort of
    structure. The kauhale, or estate or compound, was regularly comprised of hale noa (house free from
    kapu) was where all dozed together, hale mua (men\'s meeting house), hale kuke (cooking house), hale
    pe\'a (feminine cycle house) and other required dwellings. In general the building sites of the estate and
    it\'s buildings was dictated by geography and resources.</string>

    <string name="mea_pani">Long before the human settlement of the Hawaiian island chain, the Islands were devoid of
    plant or animal life. Over thousands of years seeds, insects and birds made their way to the
    Hawaiian archipelago. Populating the Islands this way was slow - it is estimated that only one
    plant every 90,000 years was added to the Hawaiian landscape.</string>

    <string name="pahu">Long ago, Oahu\'s ancient inhabitants drew their water supplies from crisp water springs, lakes, streams,
    and shallow wells. Fantastically, a populace that may have added up to many hundreds of thousands
    blossomed on the island through shrewd administration of their water assets. Strict Kapu, or laws,
    representing water assets were implemented. The Kanawai, or “laws of water” became a tradition that
    strictly adhered to. Drinking water could only be drawn from the upper sections of the stream. Bathing
    and cleaning was to be done downstream. Harming water system frameworks or hurting the water
    source was grounds for serious punishment. Water protection was an life sustaining tradition that must
    be adhered to. Living on an island surrounded by ocean salt water, the ancient know the importance of
    water conservation and management.</string>

    <string name="papa_hee_nalu">Surfing was actually the "Sport of Kings" in Hawaii. Ancient Hawaiian royalty flaunted their surfing
    abilities on Waikiki Beach and other surf spots around Oahu. In the mid twentieth century, legendary
    surfer and Olympic swimmer Duke Kahanamoku, who is native to Ohau, growing up in Waikiki,
    introduced the sport to the world. In the 50\'s, the North Shore\'s Waimea Bay became the birthplace of
    big wave surfing hosting such famous surf spots as The Bonzi Pipeline and Sunset Beach</string>

    <string name="pele">Kohola (humpback whales) are one of the bigger types of baleen whales, with full grown males ranging
    in the vicinity of 40 and 52 feet and weighing up to 45 tons. Regardless of their size, humpback whales
    are shockingly graceful creatures. Keep a keen eye toward the sea and you may see one "breach,"
    moving up to 40 percent of its body out of the water and landing on it\'s side in an enormous splash. In
    the event that you\'ve ever heard a whale tune, you\'ve tuned in to a male humpback whale. Their eerie
    songs can be heard underwater from up to twelve miles away.</string>

    <string name="pilikua_nui_wailele">Kane is Hawaiian lord of the forest and trees. Kane was the main lord of the considerable divine beings
    named by the Hawaiians. He spoke to the divine force of multiplication and was adored as predecessor
    of both royalty and commoners. Kane is the maker and gives life related with first light, sun and sky. As
    indicated by the late version of the Kumuhonua legend, he shaped the three universes: the upper
    paradise of the divine beings, the lower paradise over the earth, and the earth itself as a garden for
    humankind; the last he outfitted with ocean animals, plants, and creatures, and designed man and
    woman to occupy it. No human sacrifice or difficult custom was required in the love of Kane.</string>

    <!--New qrcodes/locations-->
    <string name="redcoats">Why did the British soldiers wear red uniforms? In 1645, this color was adopted when the first
    permanent army was raised. Red was not used in order to hide blood stains. Rather, every army adopted
    certain colors as their national colors. French soldiers tended to wear blue; Russians wore green; British
    wore red</string>

    <string name="gents">More people in the world have mobile phones than toilets, according to the United Nations.
    There are more TVs in Afghanistan than there are toilets. Interestingly, ninety percent of the population
    has TVs while only 7% has flush toilets.
    The average person will spend three years of their life on the toilet.
    Toilets are in tune: most toilets flush to E flat.</string>

    <string name="bbq_wheel">What were the Revolutionary War soldires rationed to eat? 1 lb. beef, or 3/4 lb. pork, or 1 lb. salt fish,
    per day; 1 lb. bread or flour, per day; 3 pints of peas or beans per week, or vegetable equivalent; 1 half
    pint of rice, one pint of Indian meal, per man, per week; 1 quart of spruce beer or cider per man per
    day, or nine gallons of molasses, per company of 100 men per week; 3 lbs. of candles to 100 men per
    week, for guards; 24 lbs. soft, or 8 lbs. hard soap, for 100 men per week. One unofficial ration was
    vinegar that made water secured from nearby creeks, rivers, and lakes more potable and added flavor to
    food. Vinegar\’s antiseptic properties also proved beneficial.</string>

    <string name="climbing_rocks_face">Jordan Romero (born July 12, 1996) is an American mountain climber who, on May 22, 2010, became
    the youngest person to climb Mount Everest. He was 13 years old when he reached the summit.</string>

    <string name="squirrel_and_saw">The squirrels of California have spent the last 10 million years in an arms race with rattlesnakes, and
    they\’ve come up with a couple clever ways to fend off the predators. They have fantastic reflexes, and
    can react quickly enough to dodge a snake during the fraction of a second that it takes for the reptile to
    lunge. The snakes need to be sure they\’re attacking their potential meal with the utmost surprise or it\’s
    not worth the energy to leap out. Rattlesnakes sense their prey using infrared. If the squirrels notice the
    snakes first, or enter an area where an ambush is likely, the rodent raises its tail and floods it with
    blood. This causes the tail to become warm, which stands out like a beacon to the snakes. While this
    may sound like literally the worst possible maneuver, the snakes recognize the gesture as a “I know
    you\’re there, so you’re not going to surprise me,” and so don\’t even bother to attack.The same squirrels
    have also come up with a way to deter predators that track using scent. They find a dead rattlesnake,
    chew its skin, and then lick themselves. This leaves the squirrels smelling like snakes, and scientists
    believes this tricks animals into thinking that the squirrels\’ burrows are actually home to a few feet of
    coiled, venomous danger, rather than a tasty mammalian snack.</string>

    <string name="school_house">Originally, the Oak Glen schoolhouse was wood schoolhouse on skids, built in 1889 and used for 38
    years. It was moved by a team of horses from one side of the glen to the other. Its most permanent
    home was on the Wilshire Ranch next to the creek across the road from where the stone schoolhouse is
    located today. There was also a playground for the children and a corral nearby for the horses tha were
    used as transportation to school.
    In 1927, the community decided to build a two story permanent structure. It had standard “stick”
    framing with an exterior of stones brought by horse and sled from Mill Creek.</string>

    <string name="feed_station">Corn and its by products are also found in many non-food items such as fireworks, rust preventatives,
    glue, paint, dyes, laundry detergent, soap, aspirin, antibiotics, paint, shoe polish, ink, cosmetics, the
    manufacturing of photographic film, and in the production of plastics.</string>

    <string name="concervency_sign">The Wildlands Conservancy
    Founded in 1995, The Wildlands Conservancy (TWC) is dedicated to preserving the beauty and
    biodiversity of the earth and to providing programs so that children may know the wonder and joy of
    nature.
    In working to achieve this mission, TWC has established the largest nonprofit nature preserve system
    in California, comprised of fifteen preserves encompassing 147,000 acres of diverse mountain, valley,
    desert, river, and oceanfront landscapes. These preserves are open to the public free of charge for
    passive recreation, including camping, hiking, picnicking, birding, and more.
    Ultimately, saving our treasured landscapes from development means educating and instilling a love for
    nature in future generations. For this reason, TWC is also the state\’s nonprofit leader in providing free
    outdoor education opportunities for California youth. Through these programs and our reverent
    stewardship of preserves—visited by nearly half a million people per year—we foster a love and
    respect for life in all of its magnificent forms.</string>

    <string name="wilsher_peak_mountian_siloette">As you look at the peak you are also looking at the southern most end of the infamous San Andres
    Fault. Hang on!</string>

    <string name="tennis_court_net">A tennis match takes approximately 2.5 hours. The ball is only in play for approximately 20 minutes of
    the 2.5 hours. The longest match was 11 hours and five minutes long. It took place over a period of
    three days.</string>

</resources>
